<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/AgileProjectManagement/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/AgileProjectManagement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-26T01:39:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AgileProjectManagement/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Agile Project Management Manual</title><subtitle>A site about project management.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The History of IT Project Management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AgileProjectManagement/agile/it/project/management/2019/02/25/Project-Management.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The History of IT Project Management" /><published>2019-02-25T15:47:06-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-25T15:47:06-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/AgileProjectManagement/agile/it/project/management/2019/02/25/Project-Management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AgileProjectManagement/agile/it/project/management/2019/02/25/Project-Management.html">&lt;p&gt;Introduction (Diamond)
Project management has been around since early civilization. However the ideology of it didn’t appear until the 1950’s, making it fairly new development in the history on project management (Westland, 2018). Due to the broadness of the term “Project management,” we will narrow our focus on the history of modern IT project management (Westland, 2018). First, we will explore the development of the gantt chart which was created by Henry Gantt. Next, we will look at the critical path technique and how it plays an important role in IT project management. Next, we look into an organization as well as an institution that began broadcasting project management as an important to skill to been learned. Next, we will delve into the theory of constraints and how it affects IT projects. Lastly, we will look at the development of the two main project management methodologies and how they differ.
The Gantt chart development - Henry Gantt (Diamond)
    In 1917, Henry Gantt innovated a scheduling diagram that is a visual timeline for users to pinpoint tasks as well as their durations (Westland, 2018). In 1931, the first implementations of the Gantt chart was conducted in the Hoover Dam project. Since then, The Gantt Chart has now become one of the essential tools used in managing IT projects (Haughey, 2014).
The Critical path (Adesoji)
In the 1950s, Morgan R. Walker, James E. Kelley, Booz Allen Hamilton contributed several methods for discerning the best way to complete a task with the least amount of time and slack (Ray 2018). The accumulation of their findings is regarded to as the Critical Path methodology. The Critical Path itself is measured as the longest distance between the beginning and end of the project, and takes into account things such as the earlier start date, the latest end date, and the float or slack (the maximum delay of a task before it affects overall scheduling)(Ray 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in The Critical Path methodology is to list tasks that need to be completed. Then the duration of each task is annotated, along with dependencies and milestones. After everything is calculated, you gain the full and maximum length estimated for the project. These things are then contrasted with the earliest finish date and latest start date, as well as the Crash (the shortest time in which a task can be scheduled in order to sustain quality). Once the Critical Path is established, it must be monitored to maintain functionality. One way to monitor it is to create a network diagram that can illustrate activities, or a Gantt chart that automates and modulates time calculations (Ray 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The International Project management association (Avery)
    The international Project management association(IPMA), founded in 1965,, is a federation of 70 Member Associations who. The member associations develop project management competences in their geographic areas of influence, interacting with thousands of practitioners and developing relationships with corporations, government agencies, universities and colleges, as well as training organizations and consulting companies. The IPMA was originally in Europe but has since spread across the world to places such as Australia, Africa, North and South America, Middle East, and Asia.
Project management institute (Avery)
    Founded in 1969, the project management institute(PMI), is now the leading not-for-profit professional membership association for the project management profession. With professional research and resources they are able to deliver value to almost 3 million professionals around the world allowing them to further improve the quality of their careers which also allows for the profession to mature. The PMI offers 8 different certifications that recognize the capability and understanding, including the certificate renowned as the global gold standard - Project Management Professional certification.
Theory of constraints (Adesoji)
In 1985, Eliyahu M. Goldratt, an Israeli Business Management Export published The Goal (Landau 2018). In the book, many methods and ideas for project management were explored, particularly a handful of assertions regarding the theory of constraints. Essentially, the theory of constraints is the idea that each individual constraint is an obstacle blocking management systems from achieving their ultimate goals (Landau 2018). It operates of the assumption that organizations are managed through the metrics of Throughput, Operational Expenses and Investment. Throughput is the rate at which you spend, earn and invest, and can be measured through profit, Investment Returns, Productivity and Investment Turns. Operational Expenses are the amount of money that is used to create new goal units, and investment is the next amount of currency invested in infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Constraints can be damaging to each one of these metrics, but what is a constraint? A constraint is anything that limits the productivity or established scope of a project. They can be both internal and external, ranging from market demands to production surpluses. Once a constraint is identified, Focused Processing (the method used to find and isolate constraints) is used to alleviate the issue, the team will decide upon the best way to exploit it within the available resources, and distribute the solution to all portions of the project, and repeat until the effects and fully eliminated (Landau 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Methodologies (waterfall, agile, scrum) (Christopher)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion (Diamond)
    In conclusion, IT project management is a modern form of project management and is a fairly new development in its history. Starting from Henry Gantt, who created Gantt chart that is now an essential tool for managing projects. From there researchers wanted to find the best way to manage tasks in the least amount of time, which is when the critical path methodology came about. In this method, all the tasks  for a project are listed as well as its duration so that the people working on a project can estimate the duration of a project. The international Project Management Association (IPMA) was founded in 1965, where a group of project managers networked with one another to share information about their experiences in a project (Haughey, 2014). A few years later the Project Management Institute (PMI) was founded by five volunteers that wanted provide education to make project management a profession. In 1985, the theory of constraints was developed that explored how constraints were obstacles in a project that can potentially affect its progression. Lastly we discussed the Project management process methodologies that are incremental in nature. Waterfall was one of the first processes until the emergence of Agile. They do differ, therefore it’s important for a team to understand this and pick a process that best fits their project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References: (Place your websites below)
https://www.projectsmart.co.uk/brief-history-of-project-management.php
https://www.projectmanager.com/blog/history-project-management
https://www.projectmanager.com/blog/understanding-critical-path-project-management
https://www.projectmanager.com/blog/theory-of-constraints
https://www.pmi.org/
https://www.ipma.world/?gclid=Cj0KCQiAwc7jBRD8ARIsAKSUBHJAPU1MEe7HEYvpFLQc7iDV8ImWMrzS0E6NS1ypi19eii-81pZJ40YaAhnfEALw_wcB&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Introduction (Diamond) Project management has been around since early civilization. However the ideology of it didn’t appear until the 1950’s, making it fairly new development in the history on project management (Westland, 2018). Due to the broadness of the term “Project management,” we will narrow our focus on the history of modern IT project management (Westland, 2018). First, we will explore the development of the gantt chart which was created by Henry Gantt. Next, we will look at the critical path technique and how it plays an important role in IT project management. Next, we look into an organization as well as an institution that began broadcasting project management as an important to skill to been learned. Next, we will delve into the theory of constraints and how it affects IT projects. Lastly, we will look at the development of the two main project management methodologies and how they differ. The Gantt chart development - Henry Gantt (Diamond) In 1917, Henry Gantt innovated a scheduling diagram that is a visual timeline for users to pinpoint tasks as well as their durations (Westland, 2018). In 1931, the first implementations of the Gantt chart was conducted in the Hoover Dam project. Since then, The Gantt Chart has now become one of the essential tools used in managing IT projects (Haughey, 2014). The Critical path (Adesoji) In the 1950s, Morgan R. Walker, James E. Kelley, Booz Allen Hamilton contributed several methods for discerning the best way to complete a task with the least amount of time and slack (Ray 2018). The accumulation of their findings is regarded to as the Critical Path methodology. The Critical Path itself is measured as the longest distance between the beginning and end of the project, and takes into account things such as the earlier start date, the latest end date, and the float or slack (the maximum delay of a task before it affects overall scheduling)(Ray 2018).</summary></entry></feed>